Guide to the Clifford E. Baker Photographs of Stanford Student Life
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Clifford E. Baker photographs of Stanford student life
1955-1959
PC0109
Baker, Clifford E.
1.75 Linear feet
Images are primarily of student life in Wilbur Hall (a men’s dorm at the time), 1955-56, but also include images of students at Pescadero State Beach, at Rossotti's Beer Garden, a crew race, and water polo. The prints in this collection were re-mastered and printed in 2007-08.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Images are primarily of student life in Wilbur Hall (a men’s dorm at the time), 1955-56, but also include images of students at Pescadero State Beach, at Rossotti's Beer Garden, a crew race, and water polo. The prints in this collection were re-mastered and printed in 2007-08.
Access Terms
Baker, Clifford E.; College students--California--Stanford.; College students--United States--Conduct of life.; Photoprints.; Stanford University--Students.; Student life.
Collection Contents
- Photographs
  - Beach Scenes
    - Tom Welch, George Flamer and Bill Robbins studying at Pescadero State Beach, Spring, 1956; 223 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - John Phelps at San Mateo Co. beach, 1955-56; 238 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Santa Cruz beach party with Eduardo Maal, John Carswell, and Dick Kylberg, 1956 Spring; 229 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cedro I Basketball Team
    - Cedro I basketball team in Encina Gym: Bill Harsell, Dave Cunningham, Mike Cory, John Carswell, Jack Brown, George Flamer, 1956; 119 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cedro I team plays intramural basketball, Encina Gym, 1956; 120 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cedro I Residents, Wilbur Hall
    - Bill Robbins reads letter from his girlfriend with John Carswell (left) and Don Proudfoot looking on - Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bill Robbins Studying, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955; 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Gerry Marer - Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955; 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Frank Alviso and Frank Christensen served bread and jam by Bill Robbins, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955; 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Jack Brown takes a study break, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 6 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bill Harsell watches as Bob Cahill works on something very small, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - John Carswell studying in his room, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bill Harse II (left) and David Cunningham - Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bill Hartman, George Flamer, Topm Wigdale lift weights in Baker's room, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955; 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gathering in John Carswell's room, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, (Eduardo Maal, Dave Cunningham, bill Hartman, Scott Catlett, John Carswell), 1955-56; 13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Frank Christensen and Bill Robbins, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 23 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bill Robbins and Frank Christensen (room mates) Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Jay Precourt studying in his room, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Jack Brown and Bill Harsell play handball in Wilbur Hall courtyard, 1956; 43 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Art Danforth reads newspaper at Bob Cahill's desk, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 53 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mack Taylor, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 55 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John Carswell and Gerry Maher read Sunday SF newspaper in Baker's room, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 56 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Unidentitied student and Bill Hartman read Sunday newspaper in Baker's room, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 58 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John Phelps, Mike Cory, Bill Harsell in poker game, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 78 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Tom Welch playing poker, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 79 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Frank Christensen decorates George Flamer, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 111 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - John Carswell naps, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 144 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bill Robbins and John Carswell give the photographer the "finger" or the "bird" (with Tom Wigdale in background), Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 109 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jay Precourt, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 113 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jack Brown and Bill Harsell arm wrestle, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 114 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - John Phelps helps Mike cory, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 126 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jay Precourt, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 148 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - George Flamer critiques John Carswell's haircut, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 150 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - George Flamer leaves John Carswell's room, Cedro I, Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 151 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mike Cory, Jack Brown and unknown student in front of Wilbur Hall Dining hall, 1956; 211 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jay Precourt shows off his "new" car, Wilbur Hall parking lot, 1956; 213 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dining Hall, Wilbur
    - Bill Harsell and John Phelps go through cafeteria line with unidentified "hasher," Wilbur Hall, 1955-56; 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wilbur Hall, dining hall (lunch) with Bob Cahill (extreme right) and Gerry Marer (white shirt), 1955-56; 30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Jack Brown talks, Wilbur Hall dining room, 1955-56; 36 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - George Flamer eating luch ("George hungry, George eat!"), Wilbur Hall dining room, 1955-56; 38 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Holladay House Residents, Stern Hall
    - Lunch at Holladay House, Stern Hall (Al Salcido, Dave Ward, Bill Abernathy, Dave Wallin, Jon Peterson, Rich Van Slyke), 1958; H7 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bob Bollen in Holladay House bathroom, Stern Hall, 1958-59; H6 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Roy MacGregor and Tim Anderson Sodd, Holladay House, Stern Hall, 1958; H15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Roy MacGregor and Tim Anderson Sodd, Holladay House, Stern Hall, 1958; H16 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Perry Lambird addresses Holladay House students at lunch, Stern Hall (Bob Bollen, Herb Kierulf, Dick Van Slyke, Roy MacGregor, Dave Wallin), 1957-58; H8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bridge game in Holladay House lounge, Stern Hall (Robbie Martin, Rodney Hawes, Kent Kepler, Bob Burco, and John ?), 1958; H22 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mike Stanton plays castanets in front of Playboy Magazine Playmate centerfolds, Holladay House, Stern Hall, 1958; H37 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Roy McGregor sleeps in our room under his Peruvian alpaca blanket, Holladay House, Stern Hall, 1957; H85 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Labor Day Weekend Trip
    - Bob Bollen reads map on trip to ghost towns - Bodie, CA, and Aurora (NV), 1958 Sep; H44 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bob Bollen dresses, Aurora (ghost town), Nevada, 1958 Sep; H47 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bob Bollen with gun, Labor Day, Aurora, Nevada, 1958 Sep; H49 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Rosotti's Beer Garden
    - Rossotti's Beer Garden (Larry Wagner, Herbert Kierulff, Jerome Ginsburg, Perry Lambird, Bob Pense, Tim Anderson Sodd, Paul Thiess, Bob Hamrdla, Joe Hooker), 1958 Spring; H43 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sunbathing on Campus
    - "Wilbur Beach" inner courtyard of Wilbur Hall (Tom Wigdale, Bill Hartman, John Phelps, Jack Brown), 1955-56; 40 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Trampoline, Wilbur Hall
    - Trampoline in Wilbur Hall Courtyard with Scott Catlett, Jack Brown, Bill Harsell, and Frank Christensen, 1956; 45 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Trampoline in Wilbur Hall Courtyard with Scott Catlett and Frank Christensen, 1956; 47 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Scott Catlett on Trampoline, with Art Danforth, Wilbur Hall courtyard, 1956; 50 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Water Sports
    - Stanford crew race, Redwood City Harbor, 1959 Autumn; S7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Members of Stanford's water polo team watch action, Encina Gym pool, 1959 Fall; S38 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Water polo team at Encina Gym pool, Fall, 1959; S38 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Wilbur Hall, Exterior
    - Wilbur Hall, 1955 Sep; 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Digital copies of images, 4 optical disc(s) (CD-R) (Box 2)